We welcome in general manager John
Spitek. John, thanks for a few minutes
today. Want to jump right in with free
agency and start with Tyler Linderbaum.
How did you pull that off from
evaluating him, understanding how good
of a player he would be here, and
closing that deal so quickly?
Well, it was it was a unique situation
with him, you know, not getting his 5th
year option picked up. And and then and
that happens with with centers in
particular just because of the way the
contract and the 5th year option looks,
but
you know, I give a lot of credit to our
entire pro department, Ben Chester,
Jordy Jordan, uh Brian Stark, and B
Hunt. I mean,
that was a guy that we targeted early
and just we thought, you know, with the
way that a lot of times those guys do
they go with with a player of that
caliber a lot of times those guys get
get done before free agency starts. Um
and he didn't. And so,
you know, once once it was clear he was
going to hit the market, we we made our
best offer. We we had a lot of great
conversations with Clinton, the coaching
staff, and and how important the center
is in this offense that we're going to
run. And particularly a player of his
caliber and his his traits. And so, you
know, we we tried to make him an offer
he couldn't refuse. What was it like
getting him in the building? What did
you learn about him after that?
Well, he's you know, we we go back to
our college evaluations of him and then
really the character, too. I mean, we
read all that stuff, too. Just to have
an idea of what the what the player is
and what the person is that we're
getting.
And he's just like you'd expect. I mean,
I I was around Tristan Wirfs for many
years in in Tampa and those those big 10
linemen are near and dear to my heart
just with my background and you know,
they're cut from the right kind of cloth
and Tyler certainly is that kind of
person. Jalen Neller, I watched him play
at Bishop Gorman when he was in high
school. Speedy. What was that process
like? You had to add to the wide
receiver room before the draft. How was
his addition really going to change the
way you run this offense?
Well, I don't know if it's going to
change it other than it was just we're
trying to find a good player at that
position. You know, we were young there
last year. Um
you know, he's a he's a more proven vet
and I think the cool thing about him is
is is he's really was the fourth option
there when you look at the the two
receivers they have, both first-round
picks, both excellent players, and then
and then the tight end they have there,
too. And you know, whenever he was asked
to produce, whenever he had to step in
if those guys were dinged up or whatever
in Minnesota, you know, he he performed.
And um he's he's got a lot of the traits
we look for in a wide receiver. He's a
great kid. My my only gripe with him is
he's a Spartan, but you know, I was over
willing to overlook that to to get a
player of like him in the building. We
all know with the Max Crosby trade not
going forward in Baltimore. We'll get to
the defense coming up here. And now the
fact that he's back in the building as
you continue to build this roster. Well,
my relationship with Max since I've
gotten here has been great. You know, we
had a lot of conversations throughout
the season, at the end of the season,
obviously, through the off-season. And
and obviously, we were presented with a
with a challenging and and difficult
decision to make. And you know, things
have a way of going a certain way and
work it out the way that they're
supposed to. And you know, we welcome
him like he never left cuz he really
never did. And um it's exciting to see
him to work hard and attack the rehab
like we know. And I I know you know,
he's going to be back ready to rock in
in August this year and and have a a
bunch of many good years ahead of him
still. Nakobe Dean and Quay Walker, wow.
I was hoping for one. A lot of fans were
calling in, let's just get one
linebacker.
What a stealth move. How did you do that
again in real time saying one's
available, maybe two, we have the cap
space to do it. I think the fans would
be fascinated to know how you pulled
those two off.
Well, we had a lot of cap space. And and
thankfully from our ownership group, we
had a lot of cash that we could spend,
too. I think sometimes people miss
you know, are misaligned a little bit on
what those matter. I mean, really at the
end of the day the the ownership group
giving us the cash to sign players of
the caliber we we we did was the most
important thing. And it was interesting
cuz they kind of came to a head at the
same time. You know, we were able to
zoom with with Nakobe with the new rules
this year. That was important to him. I
wasn't surprised that he wanted to do
that knowing how thoughtful and thorough
of a person he is.
And you know, we stayed in touch with
Quay's guys, too. And it just kind of
happened at the same time. They both
started to show a lot of interest in
coming here, which
I think to our group was really a cool
thing. I mean, it's when when people
start to seek you out a little bit and
like, hey, it's the silver and the black
and the Raiders in Las Vegas is where I
want to go. Um that's that's a that's a
neat thing to be a part of. And you
know, we had some quick but strategic
discussions about could we pull this
off? Would it make sense? How would we
play it? How would we play them in the
scheme? You know, um conversations with
the coaching staff and in a matter of
like, I don't know, 15 or 20 minutes it
felt like they they both made
commitments to to come join us here.
They're like missiles all over the
field. So, you look at the tape and
you've seen them get behind the line of
scrimmage. They could cover. Sideline to
sideline, is that something you were
looking forward to seeing guys that can
stay on the field and make explosive
plays?
Well, with the with the game the way it
is now, they've got to be able to run
and play at that position. You know, I
mean, that you're in you're in sub
groups a lot. And so, if you if they
can't play in, you know, nickel and dime
and and all the sub packages, then you
really end up with a kind of a one-down
linebacker. And these guys are not that,
you know, they can cover, they can run
sideline to sideline.
They could both can pressure the
quarterback, which is which is really
important in our scheme. And um you
know, they're the right kind of people.
They they they had a a great upbringing
at the obviously at the University of
Georgia. And we all know what that
program's about. And it really is who
they are. And
um you know, they both were they both
have been captains in the past. And then
we expect them to come in with that kind
of leadership. And and they're both
young, too, which is really cool thing.
What was your thought process on Malcolm
Koonce coming off the injury the year
before, his production when you said
we're going to bring him back on a
one-year deal, and then Quitty Paye on
top of that. So, more guys that can get
to the quarterback. How did that come
about?
Well, with Malcolm, um
you know, obviously coming off the ACL
injury in the the previous season in
2024,
you always expect those to take a little
bit of time. You know, even if they're
totally healthy, there's still that a
lot of those guys have talked about the
mental block. Like I got they got to get
over the hump. And I think we started to
see that with Malcolm
in the second half of the year and
really like in December where he kind of
hit his stride and you kind of got to
see the Malcolm Koonce I think that we
were all used to seeing. And
you know, we we I probably let too many
good players walk out of the building
last year. And we were determined not to
let let that happen this year. And so,
when
you know, we got to talking to Malcolm
and his his representatives, and we felt
like there was a deal in place that made
a lot of sense to bring him back. And
then with Quitty, you know, I had to
balance the for my for my own psyche I
had to balance the the Michigan State
ad. So, we had to get a Michigan man in
here. But you know, Quitty's Quitty's
had been a guy I I think we've all had a
lot of respect for going back to his
Michigan days. He was a first-round
pick. He's tough, he's violent, he's
physical, he does things the right way.
Um he's had good production in his
career. He's a great teammate. And you
know, I we we were just trying to add
good players at a premium position. And
um we were excited that those two guys
uh well, that Malcolm came back and that
that Quitty joined us. Same thing with
Eric Stokes, not letting a good player
out of the building. How did he impress
you last year through the record, the
struggles of the team when you said
that's a guy who's not getting out of
the building? Just a really super
professional approach from Eric, you
know, detailed about the right things.
You know, I'd see him in the cafeteria
studying film, you know, when guys were
hanging out. Not that guys can't hang
out, but like just very intentional with
his process, with his practice prep. You
know, one of the
one of the things that we were curious
to see last year cuz he had had an
injury history in in Green Bay was, you
know, could he could he stay healthy?
And he he played 16 games last year,
too. And that was good to see. And
you know, when
when he was asked to cover, he covered.
And you know, there weren't a lot of
balls that went his way, which
when you're a good cornerback, you don't
get a lot of balls thrown your way. And
and we just we just wanted at a at an
important position and and a maybe one
that we were a little bit thin at, we
couldn't let Eric Stokes walk out of the
building. How do you feel about cap
space going forward to sign this draft
class after the money you spent already,
the money you still have left? It must
be fascinating to you as a young GM to
see the numbers, how you played those
numbers correctly, and what you have
left. Yeah, well, we're we're up against
it now. So, you don't I don't want the
fans to expect a lot of big things
coming. And we you know, the owners were
very generous and our cap space is
tight. And
um you know, we'll have we'll have
plenty of room to sign the draft picks
again like Tom Delaney and his crew have
done a good job setting us up for that
and in the years to come. But there's no
stress about signing the draft picks.
We'll get all those guys done. On a
personal note from last year, your first
time as a GM before free agency and the
draft, how have you evolved this year?
What have you learned about yourself?
Um
it's a great question. I you know, I've
learned
to be patient. Um
but when when you need to be aggressive,
you have to go for it. And you know, I
think I think
we were you know, the saying upstairs
this this this free agent class was
intelligently aggressive. You know, we
weren't going to get out over our skis.
We weren't going to create our own
urgency. But when the opportunity
presented itself,
you know, we were going to let it rip.
And you know, if in free agency if the
worst thing that you hear is no, then at
least you know you gave a a great offer
and your best shot. And you know, I can
live in that world. And you know, we
were just fortunate this year with with
strategically how we put it all together
and then the group work that we did in
the personnel department and with the
coaches that
you know, we were we were able to let it
rip in some key spots and get some
really critical players brought into
this organization. How do you decide
about what pro days you're going to go
to instead of sending your staff or
scouts? I think the fans would be
interested because your schedule's
pretty tight here with what you have
coming up. So, how do you choose between
when you're getting on a plane, going to
a pro day, or staying back here?
Well, we just got to be strategic with
with with the with our time and what
makes sense. You know, we've got a we've
got a great group of college scouts that
that are at every pro day. Um that's
important to us. Um they do a great job
of reporting back. Brandon Yurgen does a
great job of organizing all that with
Brian Stark and Brendan Hunt. And
you know, we I kind of let them tell me
where where where should we go? Like
what what's the important guys to go
see? And at the same time, I've always
been a big believer in empowering our
staffs to to take charge and and and to
do the leg work and then report back. I
want them to feel ownership in that
space, too. And so, yeah, we've got to
be very detailed and strategic with with
where our time is spent this time of the
year. You know, we got a late start to
the whole process with with deciding to
wait till after the Super Bowl to hire
our head coach, which we're super
fortunate and happy that we we were able
to do that, but yeah, there's a lot of
strategy that goes into it. There's a
lot of coordination, but we've got a
great group. This is our second year
together, and you know, we're rolling
through it right now. Great segue to
coach Kubiak. So, you're trying to get
him to come here, and it's a delicate
negotiation cuz he's coaching, and he's
coaching in the Super Bowl. You close
that deal with ownership, and now you
get him in the building. What's that
been like? What type of coach are you
getting to see up close every day?
Well, he's he's been great. He's been a
great partner. Um very thoughtful,
very strategic, um extremely hard
worker, very detailed, put a great staff
together. You know, I mean, that was a
challenging thing for him because at the
ti- at that time in the calendar, a lot
of the guys that maybe he wanted or
you'd like to get or even interview,
they have jobs, and they have jobs that
they're not going to get out of. And but
Clint had a great plan. You know, we we
followed through on it, and it's it's
he's been a great great partner so far.
You know, we bounce great ideas off of
each other, you know, he and I both are
I think are very good listeners.
And um
you know, we see we see football from a
similar lens, and I think that was
reflective in
the the free agent class that we're able
to to put together, and and what I
expect the a great draft class to be as
well. There's a lot of coaches to talk
about, but with our limited time, I just
want to get into Rod Marinard and how he
was rewarded. How did that make you feel
knowing how he's put in the grind here?
You were able to see him, his connection
to this defense, the players who are
back, and how he's going to evolve as a
defensive coordinator.
Well, I mean, Rod deserves all the
credit. You know, he he's put in the
work like you said. You know, his his
unit, the D-line, has performed well
since he's been here. From, you know,
the film I've watched, he's developed
young guys. We saw Tony Hemingway in
particular take a big step forward as
the season went last year, and
you know, my only conversation with
Clint about it was just, "Hey, there's a
guy here that I think is at at a minimum
a great D-line coach, but, you know, if
I would suggest interviewing him." And
you know, that was that was up to Rod
and Clint at that point. You know, and
and Rod did a great job in the
interview. I was able to sit in on it,
and
you know, we were all very im- impressed
with the plan that he put together, and
the detail, and the energy, and the
urgency, and just
you know, the accountability and
discipline that was going to be in that.
And so, we expect big things from him.
Just one question on the draft. You have
the number one pick, we'll deal with
that afterwards. A lot of fans were
excited, but with the second round and
beyond, how excited are you to thread
the needle here because really feels
like you had a great free agency. Now to
nail a draft after what you learned last
year because you don't know how the
players are going to be, but you're
looking for a specific type of player in
year two. What's that player like?
Well, we're just going to continue to
look for great great people starting
with that love football, that that want
to that want to put in the work, that
want to be great teammates. You know,
they want to be coached, they want to be
held accountable. They they're going to
play and operate with some discipline,
and
we've got 10 draft picks right now. I'd
love to end up with more, so we'll see
if we'll see if we can make that a
reality on on draft day, but
you know, I I think the scouting
department just looks at it like we have
a great opportunity to add 10 quality
people and players to this organization
um that are young and hungry, and want
to help build this organization, and and
and send it on to a trajectory that
everybody, Raider Nation, and and all of
Las Vegas can be super proud of. Last
one, I always end with the fans. You've
been here now a little bit. What do you
think of the fans? What's your message
to the fans coming off free agency as
you head to Pittsburgh with the vibe of
Pittsburgh here as you're in the
building for the draft? It's it's
special. It really is. I mean, it's it's
more than I could ever have imagined um
taking this job. I mean, to feel the
love and
the energy and the passion from Raider
Nation is is really special. I mean,
it's it's one of one, in my opinion. And
um you know, I just just stick with us.
You know, we've got a great plan. We've
got a bunch of great people working
really hard on it, and you know, we're
going to execute it to the best of our
ability, and and we're I think we're all
really excited about
uh where we're at right now um after the
past month, and you know, we've got
really big things in our future. Thanks
for the time. Good luck in the draft.
>> you. Thanks, JT.